four things i like about the force usa
gunner barbell or that it's a
multi-purpose bar so you can easily
switch between power lifting or olympic
style lifts it has a knurling that's
more on the moderate side but still
provides a really solid grip it can
handle up to 1500 pounds and the cherry
on top it has a tensile strength rating
of 235
000 psi
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for you guys this
time i've got the force usa gunner
barbell in this video i'm going to walk
you through everything you need to know
about this bar from the price and the
features some pros and cons that i've
experienced as well as who should or
maybe should not buy this barbell but
before i get going we've reviewed a lot
of barbells on barbin.com so if you want
to browse our best list just go and
search barbin to best barbells and you
can find out for yourself which ones we
like the best
[Music]
okay so what do i like about this
barbell well for starters it's made of
black zinc you know i've reviewed a
handful of black zinc barbells and
honestly i just never get tired of
looking at them the gunner is rated to
handle up to 1500 pounds and it has a
tensile strength rating of 235 000 psi
if you don't know what that means well
essentially that's going to tell you
exactly how strong a barbell is so this
number typically ranges from 120 000 psi
to around 230 000 and this is an outlier
at right around 235 000 psi so you pair
that with the 1500 pound max weight
capacity
a lot of you elite level power lifters
are going to get some solid usage out of
this barbell the sleeves have a really
nice spin to them it's pretty common
with the multi-purpose bar i like this
one
that's going to be provided by a pairing
of stainless steel bushings and five
needle bearings in both of the sleeves
they spin really nice as i was saying
but it's not out of control so you can
definitely use this bar for any type of
power lifting you might want to do and
don't have to worry about those sleeves
spinning on their own
loading sleeves also have a grooved
pattern this is also pretty common with
a barbell like this but these are cut
deeper than the majority of barbells
i've personally used so i think you're
going to have that optimal success rate
in terms of keeping your plates in their
original placement now i would still use
a pair of weight collars just for your
own safety and just to help you out a
little bit but i think you're going to
have a really high success rate like i
mentioned
okay so with all that being said you
know there are a few things that are
definitely worth mentioning
this necessarily isn't cheap you know
regardless of which one of these options
you go with i'll dig into all that in a
minute you're going to be spending at
least around 300 you know that could
always be an issue for people
in the long run you're getting a pretty
solid deal but just know that you're
gonna have to spend at least three
hundred dollars if that's something you
don't really wanna do you know i'd
suggest going to find you know cheaper
alternative out there i know i just got
done saying i love a black sink barbell
and that's true they look great but
somebody like myself you know i'm in a
garage it tends to get pretty hot and
humid in here especially in the peak of
summer here in nashville so this isn't
going to be the optimal choice in terms
of protection from rust and corrosion so
i'm going to have to clean this barbell
more so than i would if it was stainless
steel
and then lastly i really like the
knurling right here it gives me a pretty
solid grip but knurling is really not a
one size fits all feature so you know
what works for me might not work for you
so just keep that in mind this is more
on the moderate side
if you want something super abrasive
well you're probably just going to want
a power bar and if you want something
less abrasive than this you can
definitely find that as well
[Music]
okay so in terms of pricing you have two
different options that's gonna depend on
which version of this bar you decide to
go with so if you in fact do want this
fully black zinc barbell that's gonna
cost you right around 350 bucks while
this one with the regular zinc sleeves
that's gonna be around 300
now in terms of actual protection from
rust and corrosion on your sleeves
i don't think the color is going to make
much of a difference i mean they're both
still zinc so that's definitely going to
be more of a personal aesthetic
preference so just kind of keep that in
mind if you want to save 50 bucks by all
means go for that regular zinc i think
you'll be just fine
if you don't want to spend you know 300
up front i personally don't blame you i
don't really like doing that fortunately
force usa does allow you to finance your
purchase through a firm for the fully
black zinc bar you'll be paying around
25 bucks a month and while with this one
with the regular zinc sleeves that's
gonna be around 21 a month all right so
spending right around 300 and possibly
more on just a barbell really might seem
like a lot of money
but you know when you compare it to the
rest of the market this is a pretty
solid deal because it can handle pretty
much everything you throw at it it does
have that super high tensile strength
rating as well as that high weight
capacity so you know you're getting a
lot of utility here which i personally
like i really think it's worth that
price tag you know if you compare it to
some other barbells there's some out
there that are the same price as this
and they feature a much lower tensile
strength rating and there's also some
that are more expensive and they also
feature a lower tensile strength rating
so you're getting a really solid deal
here in my opinion because this is going
to last you a really long time and since
it is so versatile it could be the only
barbell that you really ever need
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features with this
barbell let's start with the fact that
this is made from black zinc it's gonna
look really good in your gym i think it
looks great in ours but you know once
again in terms of optimal protection
against rust and corrosion might not be
it for everybody especially if you are
in a human environment so keep that in
mind i might have to clean it more often
than you really would want to
the knurling here it's pretty moderate
you know i think it feels pretty good in
my hands i have a pretty solid grip my
hands get kind of sweaty too so
hopefully that kind of says a lot if i'm
able to get a really good grip on it but
as i mentioned earlier you know knurling
is not a one size fits all feature so
you know keep that in mind if it's not
abrasive enough you might want to invest
in some lifting straps or gloves or
maybe even utilize some chalk if you
really want to this is a 20 kilogram bar
it's not available in 15 or 10 kilograms
so that's something you're looking for
you know you'll just have to keep
looking it's just not available here
once again this can handle up to 1500
pounds and it does have that tensile
strength rating of 235
000 psi
now you don't have a center knurling on
this barbell some people might not like
that i personally do i don't really like
when my chest or my back gets kind of
torn up while working out but you know
you do lose a little bit of grip if you
were to go do a power cleaner a hang
clean you know even a back squat so
that's something you know you gotta just
want to deal with if you get this
barbell you do have dual neural markings
here so these are set by the
international powerlifting federation
and the international weightlifting
federation this is going to be really
great you get identical hand placement
as you go to do you know a wide grip
style lift
once again you do have the option of
either black loading sleeves or regular
zinc loading sleeves kind of personal
preference and your personal aesthetic
you know what you like the best the
loading sleeves have a pairing of
stainless steel bushings and five needle
bearings so you're going to get a really
smooth spin spins at a pretty good rate
too that's going to be really nice as
you go to do a power clean and really
any of those olympic style and crossfit
style lifts you're going to have a
really high success rate but you know
they don't just spin on their own
so that's really nice
i really love the grooved pattern on
these loading sleeves too i mean
like i said they're cut deeper than
pretty much any barbell that i've used
and that's gonna be really nice you know
it's gonna keep my plates locked into
their original placement
especially if you toss on some weight
collars i mean those plates are not
going to move
[Music]
all right guys let's do a quick walk
around with this barbell now let's start
in the middle you know as i mentioned
you do not have a center knurling on
these on this barbell
i really like that it's not going to
tear up my chest or my back during my
lifts but i definitely get why some
people would prefer that because you
know you do have a higher chance of that
bar sticking especially with a power
clean the knurling here you know it is
pretty moderate like i said but it feels
pretty good in my hands i mean it gives
me a nice grip especially
when my hands start to sweat which tends
to happen quite a bit so that's pretty
nice you do have the dual neural
markings right here as i was mentioning
you know this inside one that is set by
the international powerlifting
federation and this one on the outside
that's by the international
weightlifting federation so you can
definitely get identical hand placement
on both ends of the barbell you don't
have to worry about that at all all
right as we go down this barbell you
will see you do have stainless steel
bushings right here you pair those up
with the five needle bearings in your
sleeves you're gonna get a really nice
spin right there now
both of these sleeves you know they're
the exact same despite the look the
aesthetic you know one's not better than
the other you're gonna get the exact
same experience regardless of which of
these versions you decide to go with and
i really love this groove pattern right
here so you toss on one of these weight
plates and you know they're cut so deep
that you're gonna have a really high
success rate in terms of keeping this
plate in its original placement but as
always you know i definitely suggest
throwing a pair of weight collars on
here you know snap that into place and
this really isn't going to move as that
bar is dropped on the ground
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the force
usa gunner barbell well honestly i think
just about everybody should consider
this bar if you're looking for a new one
if you're new to weightlifting you know
the knurling here is pretty moderate
it's not going to tear your hands up but
you know if you're you know more
experienced and you do have some
calluses already on your hands i still
think you're going to get a pretty solid
grip from the knurling right here
it also has a super high weight capacity
and that elite tensile strength rating
that i was talking about so if you're
really tossing some heavy weight around
this bar is going to be able to handle
it and since it is a multi-purpose bar
you know you're getting a lot of
versatility here so
you combine all those things together
and i really think this is money well
spent in my eyes
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase this barbell well
you know if you're looking for a bar
that's specifically meant for power
lifting or olympic and crossfit style
lifts i would definitely suggest going
after a specialty bar this one can
handle all of that but you know there's
certain qualities that this might not
have that you're really looking for for
your specific style of lift
if you're somebody looking for a smaller
barbell well you know it's not available
here this is only available in 20
kilograms so if you're looking for a 15
or 10 kilogram barbell well you should
have to keep looking and you know
if you're like myself you're in a humid
garage i have ac in here but you know
say you don't well this black zinc
probably isn't going to be
the ideal solution for you in terms of
longevity and you know preventing rust
and corrosion if that describes your
environment i'd probably suggest just
going after a stainless steel barbell
[Music]
all right well that's a wrap on today's
review over the force usa gunner barbell
honestly guys this thing is a beast in
the gym you know you can throw almost
anything you want at it because it does
have a moderate knurling and sleeves
that spin at a really high rate thanks
to those stainless steel bushings and
the five needle bearings you know you're
going to be able to do your olympic
style lifts but you know the knurling is
also
pretty solid in my opinion it's pretty
grippy at the same time so you can
definitely do those power lifts
especially since it has that elite
tensile strength rating of 235 000 psi
and that high weight capacity of 1500
pounds you combine all that with the
fact that you're spending less than 400
and no more than 25 bucks a month
regardless of which version you decide
to go with
and i think you've got a pretty sweet
deal but remember you know if you are
looking for a barbell that's
specifically for power lifting or maybe
even olympic style lifts you know i'd
probably suggest going after a specialty
bar and you know since this is made from
black zinc and it's not stainless steel
if you're in a human environment it's
going to require some more tlc than a
stainless steel bar would
thanks for watching everybody i hope
this video was really helpful and that i
was able to answer some questions that
you might have
over this barbell maybe even answer some
you might haven't even thought of yet as
always stay on the lookout for my next
review but for now why don't you head
over to barband.com and you can read
more about this product right here just
search bar bend force usa gunner barbell
review
our article is going to pull right up
for you and you can read over everything
we discussed here today i'll see you all
next time
[Music]
you